PETER LITTLE

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+1 (289) 404-6620

Toronto, ON Canada

https://github.com/peterlittledev

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016 ONTARIO TECH UNIVERSITY

Bachelor Degree: Software Engineering

- GPA: 3.69
- Dean's & President's List

PROFILE

Hi! I'm Peter, a team-oriented and hardworking Senior fullstack web developer, with over 8 years of experience. I'm currently looking for the next challenge in my career.

I'm extremely passionate about two things: selfimprovement, and building great things. So, I'm most interested in a great company where I can do both. A company that I can really sink my teeth into, make a big impact and grow along the way.

I would love the opportunity to discuss potential positions in your company and how I could be a fantastic addition to your team.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GovernGPT.ai

Aug 2023 - Nov 2023

Senior Full-Stack Developer

- Responsible for working directly with the CTO and CEO to rapidly prototype various incarnations of the product during the early stages of this Y-Combinator Startup (W24).
- This included research, design, development, testing, debugging, and maintenance in Javascript, Python, and prompt engineering.

StartScreen.io

Mar 2022 - April 2023

CTO & Co-Founder

- Within the Entrepreneur First Talent Accelerator (TO3), My cofounder and I created our company and received multiple funding offers from investors.
- As Co-Founder and CTO I was responsible for the entire development lifecycle of our products. This included MVPs rapidly developed from inception to paid pilot in a week to please clients.
- Our stack was primarily: Javascript, react.js, next.js, tailwind, node.js
- I also had several non-technical responsibilities which included Customer Discovery/development, pitching, investor relations, and management of the company.

CrowdRiff.com

Oct 2020 - Mar 2022

Senior Full-Stack Web Developer

- · As a senior dev I a team of developers to the end-to-end completion of various features on our core typescript product. With sole ownership over these projects, it was my responsibility to manage all aspects of these projects. This included running all required meetings, research, planning, grooming, testing, implementation, and helping, team members.
- Increased my total code output by 55% over my first 6 months.

ICON Models & Freelance

April 2019 - Sep 2020

Model & Actor / Freelance Web Developer

 In 2019 I was scouted and signed by a top modeling and acting agency in Toronto. While working as a model I used this opportunity to do freelance development and work every day on side-projects. See pg. 2 for an overview of some of my projects.

360 Insights

July 2016 - April 2019

Full-Stack Developer

- · Scaled from 1 to 22 clients on our platform resulting in millions of transactions and 10s of millions of transaction value per month.
- Starting out as a junior developer, throughout my 3 years at 360 my role continuously grew until I was selected to take over for an outgoing team lead.
- As acting team lead, I was responsible for facilitating technical discussions, interviewing and onboarding new members, as well as representing my team in cross-team functional collaborations and meetings with management.
- My other responsibilities included: designing and implementing various features across both the front-end and back-end of our platform (react.js, node.js, SQL, no-SQL)

University of Ontario Institute of Technology 2015

Software Engineering Research Technician

 Led the complete development of a Java Windows app including design, implementation, testing, and rollout. -- See GameLink (pg.2)

Projects

CareerMapper.ai (WIP) Ai Enabled Web App		
CareerMapper.ai uses ai to design a learning path for users to follow to reach their dream job.	React.jsNext.jsTypescriptPostgres	Open.aiSupabase
Stealth Onboarding Startup Ai Enabled Web App		
An app that allowed early-stage startups to leverage ai to read their knowledge base and automatically create onboarding material for new hires.	React.jsNext.jsPostgresLangchainTailwind.js	SupabaseMixpanel
Savvy Price Tracker Chrome Extension & Web Scraper		
Savvy is a Chrome extension that uses crowdsourced data to allow users to automatically track the prices of products they see while shopping online.	React.jsWebpackFigmaNode.jsGraphQLJest	MongoDBAWSPuppeteer
LandOfRhythmos.com Website (freelance)		
Developed for a freelance client, Rhythmos is a children's musical edutainment company. I was tasked with creating a site that displayed the creativity and playfulness of the brand.	JavascriptGulpCSS (SASS)Bootstrap	PHPHTML
MensFashion.ai Cloud-based Instagram Bot		
A men's fashion Instagram account run by a cloud-based bot. The bot periodically scrapes Instagram for the best new posts and then automatically re-posts them at scheduled times. Includes an admin UI for monitoring.	Node.jsGCPFigmaReact.jsMongoDBJest	CSS in JSPuppeteerWebpack
OutfitFinds.com Web Application		
Outfitfinds.com is a fashion site for Pinterest-esk fashion browsing. Users can browse outfits, discover where to find the pieces of the outfit and shop for matching accessories using the built-in Shopify drop-shipping store.	Gatsby.jsNetlifyGCPFigma	CSS in JSShopify
TopTorial.io Web Application		
Toptorial.io is a universal web app allowing users to browse and search for top-rated programming books for various programming languages.	Node.jsSketchHerokuReact.jsReduxMocha	RedisMongoDBHTML
GameLink Windows App		
Gamelink is a platform for creating, facilitating, and grading of algorithm-based coding competitions for the faculty of Software Engineering at UOIT.	JavaMavenJUnitUML	Websockets